To groom your parrot remember that it needs to be bathed.
Parrots need to be bathed in the way that they enjoy being bathed more than the way you want to do it.
Some parrots love to get in the sink with running water.
Other parrots want to get in the shower with you.
And some just like to be misted or sprayed with a misting bottle.
The water should be warm not cold, not hot.
And then they will preen their feathers to put them in the shape that they need to be in. But also you need to pay attention to their beak.
Their beaks sometimes get soiled and scaly, and these bathes don't necessarily clean them up.
I like to every now and then take just regular vegetable oil on a paper towel and wipe their beaks.
Their toenails need to be clipped.
If they're not and you handle your bird you'll be sorry.
Because they can puncture your skin very easily with their toenails.
This little fellow right here had toenails so sharp as a tiny baby that I almost dreaded to take him out and hand feed him.
But his toenails now are long enough he can grip and watch that you don't; when you're clipping their toenails that you don't go into the quick because you can make them bleed, it also hurts the bird and then they get where they don't like you to, to handle them.
A lot of people use clippers, I like to use a Dremel because a Dremel will grind them down and you've got control of how short you actually go to grind down the toenails.